Guide to the Francis M. Kelley Papers, 1910-1969
Kelley, Francis M. papers, 1910-1969
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Francis M. Kelley Papers, 1910-1969
6546
Francis M. Kelley
2.3 cubic ft.
Correspondence, ephemera, class notes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, class notes, ephemera, and other papers from Kelley's education at Cornell University and his veterinary career in Mount Morris, New York.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Francis M. Kelley was born in Phelps, New York, in 1895. He was a graduate of the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine, Class of 1918. After graduation he opened a practice in Mount Morris, New York, which he maintained until his retirement in 1968. He died in 1982
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, class notes, ephemera, and other papers from Kelley's education at Cornell University and his veterinary career in Mount Morris, New York.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kelley, Francis M.; New York State College of Veterinary Medicine--Students.
Subjects:
Veterinary medicine--New York (State).; Veterinary medicine--Study and teaching
Places:
Mount Morris (N.Y.)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
PROVENANCE
Gift of Francis M. Kelley, M.D.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Arranged by subject.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Biography and Ephemera
Boxes 1 and 4, and map case
Series II. Education
Boxes 1-3
Series III. Correspondence
Box 3
Series IV. Business Records
Boxes 3-4
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biography and Ephemera
  - Biography and Ephemera, ca. 1910-1960, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ketchum Vaccination Ear Tags, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Cornell DVM Diploma, 1918 (Map-case 1)
  - Veterinary License, 1918 (Map-case 1)
- Series II. Education
  - General, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Class Notes
    - Physiology, Spring 1915 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Materia Medica, Fall 1915 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - General, 1915-1916 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Histology, Spring 1916 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Parasites/Bacteriology, Spring 1916 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Lecture Notes, Spring 1916 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - General Pathology, October 1916 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Lecture Notes, 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Dairy 16, Spring 1917 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - General Pathology, Spring 1917 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Special Pathology, spring 1917 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Special Pathology and Directions for Shipping Specimens to Lab, Fall 1917 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Surgery, Fall 1917 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - [Materia Medica?], 1917-1918 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Surgery, Winter 1917-1918 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Medicine, Fall 1917-Spring 1918 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Bacteriology Lab, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Embryology and Diseases of Breeding Animals (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Histology, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Lab Exercises in Materia Medica and Pharmacy (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - [Medicine?], n.d. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - [Materia Medica?], n.d. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Annotated Texts
    - Burnett, S.H. Outline of Lectures in Special Pathology. Ithaca: Carpenter, 1918., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Fish, Pierre. Examination of the Urine of the Horse and Man. Ithaca: Carpenter, 1911. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Hopkins, G.S. Directions for the Dissection and Study of the...Horse. Ithaca:New York Veterinary College, 1913. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Moore and Fitch. Exercises in Bacteriology and Diagnosis. Boston: Ginn, 1914. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Ross, H.E. A Dairy Laboratory Guide. New York: Orange Judd, 1910., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Savage, Elmer. Laboratory Notebook: Feeds and Feeding. Ithaca: Self published, 1914. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Series III. Correspondence
  - Billing, 1932-1938 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Cornell--New York State Vet College--Diagnotics Lab, 1943-1958, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Livingston County, 1937-1958 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - New York State and City Health Departments, 1939, 1942, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - New York State Department of Agriculture and Markets, 1941-1965 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - New York State Veterinary Medical Society, 1956, 1958, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - United States Government, 1937-1967 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 1932-1971 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Series IV. Business Records
  - Livingston County Herd Reports, ca. 1952-1959 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Record Books
    - Billing, 1933, 1938-1940 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Spaying, 1938-1946 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Spaying, 1946-1952 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Spaying, 1952-1958 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Spaying, 1953-1963 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Spaying, 1964-1968 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Vaccination, 1946, 1948, 1959-1960, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Vaccination, 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Form Samples
    - Brucellosis Test Records, 1958-1959, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Calf Vaccination Report, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Calfhood Vaccination Authorization, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Certificates of Spaying, 1958-1963 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Certificates of Treatment, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Certificates of Vaccination, 1960-1965 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Reports of Brucellosis Reacting Cattle Sold for Slaughter, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Quarantine Vacate Notices, 1955-1958 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Statements of Services, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Tuberculosis Test Records, 1958-1969 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Index Cards
    - Client Cards, A-Z, ca. 1925-1939 (Box 4)
    - Client Cards, Strangers, ca. 1925-1939 (Box 4)
    - Tuberculosis Case Cards, ca. 1921-1944 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 32)